

## Personal Statement

I have over 10 years experience within the emergency services. During this varied career I have deployed within specialist teams and attended numerous complex operations. Throughout these roles I have developed a strong sense of leadership, teamwork and view safety as a non negotiable.

More recently, I have undertaken various civilian roles with an emphasis on health & safety, rope access/rescue and as a medic. I am currently employed as an offshore medical instructor within a major offshore training center. Within this role I am able to impart years of experience as well as implement robust training standards, designed to keep offshore workers safe. These roles have provided a great deal of experience as well as transferrable skills relevant to a variety of industries.

Mobile +44 07918105246

Email campbellsafetysolutions@gmail.com

LinkedIn Scott Martin Classification: Restricted

# MR. SCOTT CAMPBELL

## **INSTRUCTOR CERTIFICATIONS**

OPITO Approved Medical Instructor. GWO Approved Medical Instructor. MCA Approved Medical Instructor. Train-The-Trainer.

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

NEBOSH General Certificate.

IRATA Level 1 (1000hrs).

ECITB High Risk Confined Space.

First Responder Emergency Care Medic (FREC4).

OPITO BOSIET with CA-EBS, MIST, Shoulder Measure.

GWO Blade Repair.

GWO Basic Technical Training.

GWO Basic Safety Training.

GWO Enhanced First Aid.

STCW Medical First Aid.

Personal Track Safety (PTS).

Rescue 3 Safe Working At Height.

Rescue 3 Whitewater Rescue Technician Professional.

## MEDICAL CERTIFICATIONS

Valid OGUK Medical.
Valid GWO Medical with Chester Step.
Valid PTS Railway Medical.
Yellow Fever Vaccinated.
COVID Vaccinated.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Clyde Training Solutions - Offshore Medical Instructor.

Sep 2023 - Present.

- Responsible for delivering OPITO, GWO, & MCA training to the offshore workforce. In addition, ensuring delegate safety and competence through continuous professional assessment.
- Responsible for developing specialist courses relevant to the offshore industry. One such example was in partnership with Siemens Gamesa were I subsequently consulted on bespoke 'safety-days' to refine their emergency response capability.
- Supervised high risk operations and consulted on company response to major incidents, in conjunction with senior management.

## Cell:Cm - Telecommunications Mast Supervisor.

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023.

- Supervised working-at-height teams conducting maintenance within sensitive emergency service mast sites, communicating with key stakeholders throughout.
- Responsible for ensuring that RAMS were complete and adhered to. Protecting both the workforce and the client.
- Managed delays by maintaining a proactive approach and communicated with senior management team as well as the client, via detailed progress reports.

Classification: Restricted

#### Rope Access - IRATA Rope Access Technician.

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023.

- Self-employed rope access technician with a background in offshore, geo-technical, structural, and rescue cover.
- Deployed as a medic within a wider confined space rescue team, offering a pre-hospital care capability for high risk operations.
- Maintained high standards of safety and professionalism throughout.

#### **Emergency Services - Police Officer.**

Sep 2011 - Jun 2023.

- Responded to time-critical emergencies and multiple major incidents throughout career.
- Investigated multiple major incidents submitting detailed reports to Health & Safety Executive and Crown Prosecution Services
- Delivered lifesaving care and problem solving to manage high risk protracted incidents. Maintaining extremely high standards of discipline, professionalism and confidentiality throughout.
- Risk assessed major operations ensuring the safety of the public and emergency services response teams.

## **EDUCATION**

BA (Hon) Degree – University of Strathclyde.

## **REFERENCES**

Reference 1.

Mr Archie MacIellan. IRATA Level 3. archie.macLellan@clydetrainingsolutions.com

Reference 2.

Mr Ross Reddiex.
Police Chief Inspector.
d.reddiex@sky.com